Guide to the Edward Vitale violin music collection, ca. 1700-1900
George Mason University Libraries
- An electronic box inventory is unavailable. Please contact speccoll@gmu.edu for more information.
  - Vogel Als Prophet (Bird as Prophet) from Forest Scenes by Robert Schumann Op. 82 No. 7 transcribed for Violin Solo with Piano Accompaniment by Gustav Saenger, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series 6 Air (from the Violin Concerto Op. 28) (B 435), 1916 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Claude Debussy Clair de Lune de la Suite bergamasque pour Violon et Piano, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Romance Op. 22 H. Wieniawski, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 217 Bruch Op. 26 Concerto for Violin (Schradieck) Edition for Violin and Piano, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dvorak Kreisler 5. Slavonic Dances G Major No. 3 Slavische Tanzweisen, G. Dur No. 3, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Meinem Freunde Felix Mottl. Joh. Seb. Bach's Charonne fur Violine mit Orchester-oder Klavierbegleitung bearbeitet von August Wilhelmj. Neue Ausgabe Violine Solo, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Miscellany of Favorite Pieces for the Violin with Piano Accompaniment L'Abeille (The Bee) R. Massart, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - As played by Mischa Elman Gauotte for Violin with Piano Accompaniment by Fr. Jos. Gosser Violin and Piano, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Serenade from Ballet les Millions D'arlequin by R. Drigo, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Compositions for Violin and Piano Felix Borowski Adoration, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 235 Mendelssohn Violin Concerto Op. 64 (Violin and Piano) (Schradieck), 1895 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Modern Concert Solos for Violin with Piano Hejrekati (Czardas Scene) Op 32, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 3. Niccolo Porpora Menuet, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bandanna Sketches Four Negro Spirituals by Clarence Cameron White Violin and Piano No. 4 Negro Dance (Sometimes I Feel like a Motherless Child), 1918 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Chopin, Fr. Op.9 No. 2 Notturno (Sarasate), 1903 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Modern Salon Music For Violin and Piano Georges Bizet Adagietto from "L'Arlsienne" played by Fritz Kreisler, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - To Mischa Elman Fritz Kreisler Rondino on a theme by Beethoven for Violin and Piano, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Bandanna Sketches (Four Negro Spirituals) by Clarence Cameron White No. 1 Chant (Nobody Knows de Trouble I've Seen), 1918 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Cecil Burleigh Compositions for Violin and Piano Op. 30 Six Pictures 4. Hills, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - A. Walter Kramer Op. 32 No. 1 Chant Negre An Idyl for Violin and Piano, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - C. Fischer's Edition No. 175 Fiorillo 36 Etudes or Caprices Violin (Emil Kross), 1900 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 120 R. Kreutzer Forty-Two Studies for Violin (E. Singer), 1894 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 5. Gaetano Pugnani Praeludium and Allegro, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano N. Rimsky-Korsakow Two Sketches from "Scheherazade" No. 2 Chanson Arabe, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano N. Rimsky-Korsakow Hymn to the Sun from the Opera, "Le Coq D'or", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Wieniawski, H. Op. 17 Legende, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Serenade du Tsigane (Gypsy Serenade) for Violin with Piano Accompaniment by Charles Robert Valdez, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series 5 Spanish Dances Op. 22 Pablo de Sarasate (Romaza Anfaluza and Jota Navarra), 1903 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Recital Music for Violin and Piano M. Moszkowski Guitarre, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Schirmer's Library Wol. 74 Beethoven Op. 47 Sonata for Piano Forte and Violin (Bordsky), 1894 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 770 Rode Twelve Etudes for Violin (Fr. Hermann), 1916 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Edition Peters No. 2469 Fiorillo - Spohr Etuden Etudes - Studies, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition N. 162 L. Massart The Art of Studying R. Kreutzer's Etudes for Violin, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 1389 Alard Opus 41 24 Etudes - Carices for Violin (Lichtenberg), 1921 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Eidition No. 276 Jac. Don't Op. 37 24 Preperatory Excercizes to the Studies of R. Kreutzer and P. Rode for the Violin, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Edition Andre No. 213a Alard L'art Moderne pour violon seul Op. 53 Cah. I. No 1-10, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Edition Andre No. 213b Alard L'art Moderne pour Violon Seul Op. 53 Cah II (No. 11-20), undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Collection Litolff No. 2010 saint-Lubin 6 Grand Caprices pour Violon Op. 42 (Ad. Grundwald), undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Collection Litolff No. 3115 Fr. Hermann 12 Special Etudes for the Violin (1st to 7th Position) Op. 29 Book 3, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Edition Peters No. 3029 Spohr Violin - Studien Excercices de Violon - Violin Excercises (Seeger), undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Augener's Edition No. 5646 C. De Beriot 6 Etudes brillantes Op. 17 Violon, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Edition Peters No. 2849 Kreutzer Etudes Violine II (Hermann), undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 595 P. Rovelli Twelve Caprices for the Violin (Edmund Singer), 1910 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Collection Litolff No. 2008 Alday Le Jeune 24 Etudes pour Violin Op. 4 (Ad Grunwald), undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Universal Edition No. 742 Etudes D.Anciens Maitres Pour Violon Seul 4 Campagnoli 6 Fugues (Bloch), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Volksausgabe Breitkopf and Hartel No. 410 Paganini 24 Capricen fur Violine Op. 1 (Ferd. David), undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Schirmer's Library of Musical Classics Vols 306-308, 750 H. E. Kayser 36 Elementary and Progressive Studies for Violin Op. 20 Complete in One Volume and in Three Books, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 36 Etuden oder Capricen fur Violine Solo von Fr. Fiorillo mit Zweiter Violine von Louis Spohr, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Edition Peters No. 2199 Petri Kunstler - Etuden Etudes d'Artistes - Virtuoso's Studies Violine Solo, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Edition Peters Dancla Etudes Opus 73, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Gymnastics of Violin Playing A Method for Attaining Complete Mastery of Every Phase of Violin Technics by Goby Eberhardt English German, and French text in Two Parts, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - C. Fischer's Edition No. 102 Mazas Op. 36 Suite 3 Etudes D'Artistes Violin, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Vier und Zwanzig 24 Studies for Violin in 24 Different Tunes (to be used as preperatory studies to Rode's Caprices) by Hans Sitt Op. 80 Book 1, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Vier und Zwanzig 24 Studies for Violin in 24 Different Tunes (to be used as preperatory studies to Rode's Caprices) by Hans Sitt Op. 80 Book 2, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Volksausgabe Breitkopf and Hartel No. 1463 Paganini 60 Etuden fur Violine (F. David), undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 231 Rode 24Caprices for Violin (David), 1895 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Edition Peters No. 284 Kreutzer Etuden (Hermann), undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1136 Spirit of the Lord Done Fell S. A. T. B. Spiritual Arranged by Noble Cain, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1111 Come Thou Fount of Every Blessing S. A. B Based on "Nettleton" Arranged by Grace North, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1110 The Moon Passed By S. A. T. B. by Raymond Rhea, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1121 Early to Bed and Early to Rise S. A. by Powell Weaver, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1064 Angel Voices Ever Singing S. A. by C. Albert Scholin for Children's Day or General Use, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1083 Little David, Play on Your Harp S. A. B. Negro Spiritual Arranged by Frederick Fay Swift, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1085 Sing to the Lord of Harvest by Joseph Haydn Hymn - Anthem for Thanksgiving or General Use Arranged by C. Albert Scholin, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Volume 33 February 1946 Number 5 The Volunteer Choir A Monthly Magazine (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Oberlin Choral Series Under the Editorship of Olaf C. Christiansen Choruses for Mixed Voices 23. God the Lord is Gracious, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1153 Come Light Serene and Still S. A. T. B. Based on Themes from 6th Sonata for 'Cello by Johann Sebastian Bach Freely Written by R. Deane Shure, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1141 Christian, the Morn Breaks Sweetly O'er Thee S. A. T. B. by H. R. Shelley Incidental Solo - Soprano, Bass, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1082 Lead Me Lord S. A. B. Samuel Sebastian Wesley Arranged by Rob Roy Peery, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1132 All Glory Be To God S. A. T. B. by Charles Wentworth Arranged by Noble Cain, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1137 America The Beautiful S. A. T. B. by Samuel A. Ward Festival Setting by Henry Overley, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1158 My Lord Delivered Daniel S. A. B. Arranged by Noble Cain, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1089 The Heavens Declare S. A. T. B. by Helen Jun Marth, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Belwin Octavo No. 1146 The Sidewalks of New York (East Side, West Side) S. A. T. B. by Lawler and Blake Arranged by Frederic Fay Swift, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - No. 605 The Mikado or The Town of Titipu Chorus Edition W. S. Gilbert Arthur Sullivan, edited by J. Remington, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Edition Peters No. 1078 Dancla Etudes Opus 68, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 750 Kayser Elementary and Progressive Studies for the Violin Op. 20 Complete, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Collection Litolff (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Collection Litolff No. 1581 J. Plenel 6 Petits Duos Op. 8 Arranges pour 2 Violons et Piano, undated; 1
    - Collection Litolff Six Petits Duos pour Deux Violons de I. Pleyel Op. 8 Original-Ausgabe Arrangements von Max Schultze, undated; 2
  - Edition Peters No. 1081k Dancla Duos Opus 25, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Collection Litholff Duos pour Deux Violons, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Edition Peters No. 1776b Mendelssohn Lieder ohne Worte und Kinderstucke Songs Without Words and Children's Pieces Zwei Violinen (Hermann), undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Compositionen von F. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy fur Zwei Violinen bearbeitet von C. G. Wolff und Fr. Hermann, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Edition Peters No. 1081i Dancla Duos pour 2 Violons Opus 62, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Extra Covers, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Edition Peters No. 1086f Spohr Duos pour 2 Violons Opus 150 (David), undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Collection Litholff Duos Faciles et Progressifs pour Deux Violons d'apres les Grands Maitres par Louis Schubert 3 Suite L. van Beethoven, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Edition Peters No. 1086c Spohr Duos pour 2 Violons Opus 39 (David), undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Samtliche Duette fur Zwei Violinen komponiert von Louis Spohr revidiert von Ferd. David Op. 153, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - C. Fischer's Edition No. 139 Schradieck Scale Studies for Violin, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Violin School Second Part with English and German Text Representing the Positions in 100 Excercises by Hubert Ries, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Edition White Smith No. 407 Louis Schubert Violin School Vol. 1, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Collection Litolff Violin School by Louis Schubert Op. 50 English Translation by John Orth, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Gymnastics of Violin Playing A Method for Attaining Complete Mastery of Every Phase of Violin Technics by Goby Eberhardt English, German, and French Text in two parts, Part 2, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Edition Schott S. 3537 Meerts Technik des Violinspiels Le Mecanisme du Violon, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Edition Peters No. 3361 Ondricek - mittelmann Neue Meistertechnik des Violinspiels, 1909 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 504 Hans Sitt Op. 92 Technical Studies Part 2 Exercises and Studies for the Special Development of the Right Hand Book 5, 1907 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 515 Schradieck The School of Violin Technics Section 1, 1900 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 5. Auflage Urstudien fur Violine voon Carl Flesch, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 505 Hans Sitt Op. 92 Technical Studies Part 2 Book 6, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 426 Ch. De Beriot Op. 57 Three Duos Concertants for two Violins, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Edition Peters No. 2365 Schumann Stucke aus Jugend - Album op. 68 Album a la jeunesse - Album for the Young Fur 2 Violinen (Hermann), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rob Schumann's Sammtliche Werke Ausgewahlte Stucke fur 2 Violinen arrangirt von Friedr. Hermann, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Samtliche Duette fur Zwei Violinen komponiert von Louis Spohr revidiert von Ferd. David Op. 153, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 1394 Spohr Opus 3 Duos for Two Violins (David - Svecenski), 1919 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Schirmer's Library of Musical Chairs Vol. 1394 Louis Spohr Opus 3 Duos for Two Violins Edited by Ferdinand David Revised by Louis Svecenski, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Edition Peters No. 1086b Spohr Duette fur 2 Violinen Opus 9 (David), undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Samtliche Duette fur zwei Violinen komponiert von Louis Spohr revivdiert von Ferd. David Opus 148, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Samtliche Duette fur zwei Violinen komponiert von Louis Spohr revidiert von Ferd. David Op. 148, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Samtliche Duette fur zwei Volinen componirt von Louis Spohr revidirt von Ferd. David Op. 67, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Samtliche Duette fur zwei Volinen componirt von Louis Spohr revidirt von Ferd. David Op. 67, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Deux Duos progressifs et concertans pour deux Violons par J. W. Kalliwoda Opus 70, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Deux Duos progressifs et concertans pour deux Violons par J. W. Kalliwoda Opus 70, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Trois Duos progressifs et concertans pour deux violons par J. W. Kalliwoda Opus 116, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Trois Duos progressifs et concertans pour deux violons par J. W. Kalliwoda Opus 116, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Trois Duos pour deux Violons Par P. Rode Liv. I, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Cover to Volksausgabe Breitkopf and Hartel No. 944 Spohr 50 Ubungen und Vortragsstucke aus der Violinschule I, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Collection Litolff Duos faciles et progressifs pour Deux Violons P. Rode Trois Duos Liv. 1, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Collection Litolff Duos pour Deux Violons, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1294 B. Campagnoli 101 Pieces Faciles et Progressives pour Deux Violons Op. 20 Cah. 1 (Grunwald), undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Collection Litolff No. 509 Zinkeisen 26 petits Duos pour deux Violons, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1292 Blumenthal 100 Uebungstucke (Pieces instructives et graduees) fur 2 Violinen Op. 42 Cah. II (A. Schulz), undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Collection Litolff Duos Faciles et Progressifs pour Deux Violons d'apres les Grands Maitres par Louis Schubert 2nd Suite W. A. Mozart, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 519 Viotti Duets for Two Violins Book 2 Opus 20 (Lichtenberg), 1900 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 520 Viotti Duets for Two Violins Book 3 Op. 9 (Lichtenberg), 1900 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Augener's Edition No. 5599i Alard Progressive Duets Ernst Heim Book 9 (2 Violins), undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Collection Litolff No. 922 Mendelssohn's Werke Duette uber beliebte Tonitude fur 2 Violinen, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - C. Fischer's Edition No. 130 Mazas Op. 38 12 Petits Duos I, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - C. Fischer's Edition No. 131 Mazas Op. 38 12 Petits Duos 2 Violins Book II, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Carl Fischer's Edition No. 159 I. Pleyel Op. 61 Three Duos for Two Violins, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 692 Ch. De Beriot Op. 113 Spanish Airs for 2 Violins, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1275 Louis Schubert Violin - Duette Classischer Stucke (Duos pour 2 Violins sur des Pieces celebres) Cah. 7 C. M. von Weber, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Editions Peters No. 3061a Beriot Duos pour 2 Violons Opus 57 (Hermann), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 147 I. Pleyel Op. 8 Six Petits Duos (Sonatas) for Two Violins, 1895 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Edition Peters No. 2205 Schubert Lieder fur 2 Violinen (Hermann), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Collection Litolff Duos Faciles et Progressifs pour Deux Violons Revus et doigtes par A. Blumenstengel and A. Schulz, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Collection Litolff No. 2129 Meyerbeer Beruhmte Stucke (Pieces celebres. - Celebrated Pieces) 2 Violinen (Manuel Dello.), undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Augener's Edition No. 5611 Hauptmann 3 Duos Op. 16 F. Hermann (2Violons), undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Collection Litolff No. 680 J. Wanhall 24 Duos tres-faciles et progressifs pour Deux Violons Op. 56, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Fritz Kreisler Favorite Encore Folio for Violin and Piano, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Quatre Valses Brillantes pour Violon et Piano Composees par J. W. Kalliwada Op. 103 Propriete de l'Editeur, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Edition Peters No. 2193c Mozart Violin - Concert D major (Hermann), undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 301 Franz Ries Op. 34 Suite No. 3 (G Major) For Violin and Piano, 1901 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 629 Masterpieces for the Violin Vol. 19 H. Leonard Op. 2 Souvenir de Haydn Violin and Piano (Lichtenberg), 1901 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Schirmer's Library of Musical Classics Vol. 417 Tommaso Vitali Ciaccona for Violin with Figured Bass Arranged for Violin and Piano forte by Ferd. David Revised by Henry Schradieck with a biographical sketch of the author, 1897 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Fritz Kreisler Violin Compositions La Folia par A. Corelli, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Collection Litolff Violin - Concerto von Louis Spohr Neue revidirte Ausgabe von Leopold Auer No. 11 G dur. Sol majeur. G Major Op. 70, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Fritz Kreisler Violin Compositions Fuge, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Frtiz Kreisler Violin Compositions Hungarian Dance (after Johannes Brahms), 1925 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Airs varies pour Violon avec accomagnement de Piano par Ch. De Beriot revus par Hans Sitt Vol. 1, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Fritz Kreisler Compositions for Violin and Piano 3. Tambourin Chinois, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 366 Masterpieces for the Violin Vol. 2 Wieniawski Two Mazurkas Op. 12 Legende Op. 17 Violin and Piano, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Edition Peters No. 2475b Handel Sonaten Violine and Piano Band II (Sitt.), undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano N. Rimsky-Korsakow Hymn to the Sea from the Opera, "Le Coq D'Or", 1919 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Collection Litolff P. Rode Deux Airs Varies pour Violon et Piano, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - 12 Melodies italiennes pour le Violon avec Accomgnement de Piano arrangees par Ch. De Beriot revues par Hans Sitt, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Augener's Edition No. 11474b Polaestra Pieces for Violin Solo with Pianoforte accompaniment, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Edition Peters No. 1094 Rode Air Varie Piano et Violon, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Edition Peters No. 3226 Alte Meisler de Violinspiels Old Masters of the Violin (Schering), 1909 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Alte Meister des Violinspiels fur den praktischen Gebrauch zum ersten Mal herausgegeben von Arnold Schering, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Airs Varies for Vioin and Piano (Sitt.), undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Ballade et Polonaise H. Vieuxtemps, 1895 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Edition Breitkopf Nr. 1953 Bach Violoncell-Suiten, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Anleitung zum studium der accorde fur violine xum Gebrauch am Konigl Conservatorium der Musik xu Leipxig herausgegeben von Henry Schradieck, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Grosse ausfuhrliche technik des violinspiels in progressiver systematicher ordnung vom ersten anfang bis zur hochsten ausbildung von Richard Hofmann, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Edward Keller and Otto K. Schill School of Virtuosity: 275 studies for the violin for the development of technique to artistic perfection with especial reference to the playing of double stops, 1901 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Violin exercises (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Edward Herrmann Twenty-five violin etudes for the systematic study of double-stops, 1904; 1
    - Schirmer's Library Vol. 932 Casorti Op. 50 The technics of bowing for the violin, 1909; 2
    - Schirmer's Library Vol. 922 Tartini The art of bowing for the violin with piano accompaniment, 1909; 3
    - Carl Fischer's music library edition No. 503 Hans Sitt Op. 92 technical studies Part II Book IV, 1907; 4
    - Carl Fischer's music library edition No. 291 O. Sevcik Op. 2 school of bowing for violin, book 1, 1904; 5
  - Methodes etudes et ceaux de genre pour violin par Ch. De Beriot methode de violon Op. 102, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Exercises in thirds for the violin by August Wilhelmj, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Empfehlenswerthe Werke alterer und neuerer Meister Lipinski o., undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Gruss an freunde und kunstbruder! Mehrstimmige studien fur die violine componirt H. W. Ernst, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Recent publications for violin and piano Fantasia on a theme from Lucia di Lammermoor, violin solo, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Studienwerke u. - Stucke fur Violine Adelaide von Beethoven transcription fur violine solo von Leon de Saint-Lubin, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Studienwerke u. - Stucke fur Violine Erlkonig caprice fur violine Allein Nach der Ballade von Fr. Schubert, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Willy Burmester pieces by old masters arranged and edited for violin and piano 30. Handel Piano, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Favorite recital solos for the violin with acompaniment, series 2 C. Fischer's Edition, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bruno Wollenhaupt three compositions for violin and piano, Elegie, 1906 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Willy Burmester pieces by old masters arranged and editesd for violin and piano No. 10 Bach Air on the G string, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Recital music J. Massenet Crepuscule (Twilight) transcribed by Jeno Hubay, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Austrian folk songs transcribed for violin with piano accompaniment by Fritz Kreisler, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Fritz Kreisler transcriptions for violin and piano, E. Granados, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Fritz Kreisler Freie Bearbeitugen alterer werke der violin-litteratur ausgabe fur violine mit pianoforte-begleitung Niccolo Paganini Op. 12 Non piu mesta (thema mit variationen), 1905 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Fritz Kreisler classical masterpieces for violin and piano - Niccolo Paganini Caprice No. 24, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Fritz Kreisler Freie Bearbeitugen alterer werke der violin-litteratur ausgabe fur violine mit pianoforte-begleitung Niccolo Paganini Op. 7 La Clochette, rondo aus dem 2 konzert (H moll), 1905 (Box 11, Folder 21)